



Md Yasir Azeem

Nationality: Indian Date of birth: 20/12/1987 Gender: Male

Complex Series Complex : Complex :

№ Whatsapp Messenger: +919897213241

in LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mohammad-yasir-azeem-047498219/

Website: https://techievasir.com/

• Work: Al Yamama Company Residential Area, AL Anwar , 32132 Ad Dammam (Saudi Arabia)

• Home: 13/1431 Nakhasa Bazar, 247001 Saharanpur (India)

ABOUT ME

Obsessed Cloud Enthusiast with an impressive AWS home lab. Dedicated IT professional with 7+ years of experience providing unforgettable experiences to clients while maintaining an addiction to learning Cloud technologies and DevOps. Plagued with the overwhelming urge to tinker, figure things out, and build enterprise-level AWS infrastructures.

CREATIVE WORKS

Cloud And DevOps Home Labs

[Current]

AWS Labs

- Built a hacking lab in AWS to simulate an enterprise network and vulnerable machines using Kali Linux.
- Built multiple web servers using Amazon Linux, Ubuntu, and Centos on EC2 Instance.
- Built an Application Server on EC2 Instance Using Tomcat.
- Deployed a domain controller on Windows Server 2022 along with two Windows Server 2019 machines utilizing AWS ec2 Instance and joined the domain.
- Created multiple VPCs within the Regions to simulate multiple network subnets.
- Utilized CloudWatch to monitor performance and create alerts.
- Deployed Jenkins Tools on the container for CICD for a sample application (GIT-HUB).

Home Lab - Virtualization on Home Server

- Installed and configured Proxmox on a home server, setting up hosts, networking, and storage.
- Deployed Virtual machines, and Ubuntu servers in my home lab for DevOps Learning.
- Home lab for GIT-Hub, GITLAB and JENKINS CICD.
- Home lab For Ansible, Docker.

DevOps:

- Deploy Personal Website Using HTML CSS JAVAScript BY using Docker Image and Jenkins CICD
- Deploy Multiple Web Apps using Github-CICD, Build Docker Images, and deploy to Kubernetes.
- Continuously using DevOps tools like Git, Docker, Ansible, Jenkins, Kubernetes (GCP) Terraform.

DIGITAL SKILLS

AWS / Windows & Windows Server / Linux & Linux Servers / Git / Active Directory. / VMWARE WorkStation / Docker / Kubernetes/Google Cloud Platform / pfSence / SharePoint / CLI / Apache Tomcat / Jenkins / Maven / Microservices / IT Networking and Troubleshooting / Cisco Switches / Router Configuration / LAN Infrastructure, Routing Protocal

WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Engineer

Al Yamama Company [19/11/2021 - Current]

City: Ad Dammam
Country: Saudi Arabia

Project- King Abdul Aziz World Culture and History (ARAMCO) Activities and Responsibilities

Nov/2021 - Present

- Routinely engage with the Networking Team to learn additional skills and help with the daily administration of Cisco switches and routers.
- Create and Manage Sharepoint Web Page for Project use.
- Create and manage File Servers for Backups and Storage.
- Managed and troubleshot for Microsoft Server 2012 R2 for Building Management Systems, Security Server and Lighting Servers.
- Configuration & troubleshooting of Cisco Switches, Ethernet and SPF IN the BMS system.
- Implement new server-based technologies as part of the IT department's strategic plans.
- Create and implement Active Directory Group Policies as per organizational requirements.
- Manage onboarding/offboarding processes, be the main contact with the HR Team and hold responsible for all IT equipment,
- Created a wiki of common desktop/application fixes for the support team, cutting ticket time to close in half.
- Resolve 20+ trouble tickets per day through efficient triaging of problems.
- Managing day-to-day service desk teams, coaching them, developing their skills, and building internal collaboration.

IT administrator

Glocal University [25/02/2015 – 30/07/2021]

City: saharanpur Country: India

- Create and manage Organizational Units, Manage Users.
- Group policy management.
- Deploy software with Group Policy.
- Backup and Recovery Management.
- Installation and Configuration of Active Directory / DNS / DHCP /AV Servers.
- · LAN installation, Routing,
- Cisco Routers DHCP configuration by using CLI.
- Experience in Server Hardware Knowledge, Monitoring & Administration.
- Troubleshoot server network configuration problems.
- Repairing of built computer systems and networks windows XP, Windows 7,8 and 10.
- Configuration & troubleshooting of Cisco Switches, Routers, and firewalls.
- Networks protocol support and IP address configuration. Assist users with daily operational issues.
- Performed hardware and software support and installation, Replaced defective or inadequate software packages.
- Handling Wi-Fi (wireless internet) and rectifying the problem.
- Handling Department Asset Management.
- Handling Department Budget Management & coordinating billing process.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Master Of Technology (M.Tech)

Uttarakhand Technical University [01/07/2012 - 30/06/2014]

Address: Dehradun, 247001 Dehradun (India)

Website: https://uktech.ac.in/en

Bachelor Of Technology (B.Tech)

Uttarakhand Technical University [01/07/2007 – 30/06/2011]

Address: Dehradun, 247001 Dehradun (India)

Website: https://uktech.ac.in/en